What do you mean?
It's like whoever you stop,
you find nothing worthwhile. Just pennies.
Listen, Ajamila...
You weren't always... like this...
Like what?
Well... involved in what you are now.
Why do you ask?
Just curious.
Yes, there was a different Ajamila once...
A different life...
everything was different.
And what did you do?
I was a Brahmin...
A priest.
... and then he rushes to Prahlada,
shakes him by the shoulders and screams:
"Where, where is your Vishnu? Show Him!"
And Prahlada?
Prahlada looks into his eyes
and replies with a smile:
"Dear father, look closely,
and you'll see the Lord everywhere."
And then?
And then Hiranyakashipu screams:
"So, your Vishnu is in my house?"
Prahlada replies with a smile:
"Yes, father, the Lord
is always in our home."
Then Hiranyakashipu grabs his sword
and starts swinging it, shouting:
"Vishnu! Vishnu! If You're here, come out!"
And when Hiranyakashipu saw no one,
he rushed at Prahlada
with his sword, saying:
"If your Vishnu doesn't appear before me now,
I'll cut off your head!"
And Prahlada?
Prahlada, this little boy,
tells his father:
"Here He is, my Lord,
right before you."
Hiranyakashipu points to a pillar and yells:
"Is he in this pillar?"
"Yes, father, can't you see?"
Then Hiranyakashipu grabs
his sword and with all his might
strikes the pillar...
But you know, Ajamila,
no one heard the sound of the broken pillar
Why?
Because at that moment,
there was a deafening roar of a lion,
...and the magnificent Lord Vishnu appeared.
They fought for a long time
before Lord Narasimhadev
grabbed Hiranyakashipu,
laid him on his knees
and with his sharp claws
tore him to pieces.
And so saved his dear devotee Prahlada.
And would the Lord do the same for me?
Come to me and save me from demons?
Of course, Ajamila.
The Lord's love never ceases.
Even if we forget about Him,
He continues to love us.
And is always ready to come to our aid.
This... this... this is so wonderful.
Yes, my son. This is the ultimate truth.
Father, are you okay?
Yes, my boy, I'm fine, just a bad omen.
Father
What, my boy?
Father, tell Swamiji about
what I asked you today.
Ah, yes,
During our pilgrimage,
Ajamila made an important decision
He wants to receive initiation from you.
Oh Gurudev, please accept me
as a disciple.
I ask you for this mercy.
I will not leave this path.
Never?
Never!
Well, Lochan Babu, gather your son.
Tomorrow I want to see him in my ashram.
Gurudev, so you've accepted me?
Of course, my boy.
Father, did you hear?
Yes, my boy, yes, wonderful!
Ajamila…
Yes, Gurudev.
Today marks a wonderful day, long awaited.
Are you ready to be devoted to the truth
in all circumstances of your life,
and be faithful to the Brahmanical vows?
I am ready, Gurudev.
Do you promise to follow the spiritual path
until the end of your days?
I promise, Gurudev
Name me the Brahmanical qualities
you will exhibit.
Honesty, purity, ability
to perform austerities,
calmness, freedom from anger, forgiveness,
non-violence towards any living being.
Ajamila.
Yes, father.
Have you forgotten
what you have to do today?
What are you talking about?
Ah, tomorrow we will perform...
Tomorrow at dawn
we will perform an auspicious ceremony.
Of course, I remember.
I haven't forgotten at all.
So, you should go to the forest right now
for suitable firewood.
Clean, dry, an elbow's length…
…pleasant to the eye.
Right.
Also, you should bring forest flowers.
Clean, pleasant to the eye,
and with a good fragrance.
Right. But don't smell them!
Go right now, you'll be back by lunchtime.
And after lunch, we have
some chores to do.
What? Right here? Now? Are you sure?
Please! My Goddess! Do you want me dead?
Goddess, am I a goddess? Is this gold?
Gold! All gold! Yes, Goddess!
Take it! All the gold in the world! All yours!
Please be kind to me!
Yes? Goddess!
Yes, my fool!
Father, I can't take it anymore. Where is he?
...I don't know.
Father, what should we do?
A whole day has passed,
and he's still not back.
First, calm down. Sit, eat.
You haven't eaten anything
since morning.
A whole day has passed.
The sun is about to set,
and he's still not back.
What if something happened to him?
What if he was attacked by robbers?
There are always many robbers in the forest!
Or what if he was bitten by a snake?
No!
It was a scorpion.
There are always many poisonous
scorpions in the forest.
And now my Ajamila
lies in the grass, dying from its venom.
I will go look for him!
Well, say something to me.
What?
Well, make something up.
You are so vocal, after all.
Sorry, dear, I have to go.
Won't you say a word?
Why should I?
I want to hear about
your passion one more time.
You'll hear it.
Later.
But I want it now.
Later. I'm in a hurry.
Well, tell me I'm a goddess.
Well, goddess.
Not like that! Say it as you did before!
Like this: "My Goddess"!
I didn't say that.
What?
Like this "My Goddess" - I never said that.
I didn't say it like that!
Didn't say it? Ah, you rascal!
Get away from me.
Calm down! Everything's fine.
Nothing happened.
Not fine! You're cold-hearted!
A stone, that's who you are!
Can't even be nice to me.
Yes, I can be nice... But later.
Then we'll talk later.
So, in a week?.. My goddess?
Go away.
Bye then.
No daughter, you're not going
to the forest alone. Sit down!
How can I just sit and do nothing?
I cannot live without him.
I will pray. I hope he returns soon.
Ah, daughter, daughter.
My heart hurts like never before.
Something terrible has happened to him.
Father, I feel something terrible.
You... so beautiful... like a flower...
Flower! And everyone tells me I'm a goddess!
Are you talking about that man?..
Who is he to you?
Man? So, you saw him, Ajamila?
I did.
And now what?
I don't know.
But I know. Shall I tell?
Lean in to me. I'll whisper it in your ear.
You probably also want to be with me here,
in the forest, where no one sees us?..
You probably also want me to love you?
You know, I'm ready.
Because I like you.
Do you hear me? I'm ready, Ajamila. I'm Ready.
I will be very happy if you wear this.
For me?
How lovely!
Thank you.
Why are you silent? Do you hear me?
No… No!
Well, no then.
Run home.
And if you change your mind, and want
to find me... you'll find
only…
what?
Money
Money. Coins. My love costs something.
And if you don't find it - no need,
Brahman Ajamila.
God! God! Is this a dream? No
Did this happen to me?
I have my wife Kamali! Father... My path!
What's happening to me?
Ajamila?! Where have you been? I almost died…
Ajamila. What's wrong with you?
What happened?
Nothing happened.
Where were you?
Collecting wood, flowers.
Why did it take so long?
Long? No, I was quick.
Still, Ajamila, why so long?
Nothing happened!
It just turned out that way.
Everything is fine with me!
Fine! All is good!
Ajamila!
Brahman Ajamila!
I know you have money!
There! Give it to me,
and you'll get something in return…
I'm ready, Ajamila. Ready.
Come to me! Forget everyone.
Now you have only me in your life!
I will give you what you've never experienced.
Just come to me…
Why didn't we meet earlier?
We are made for each other.
Didn't you realize that after our meeting?
I am your fate. I am your real life…
My embrace is gentler than your wife's.
Right, Ajamila? Don't deceive yourself.
I am much more skilled in love than she is.
And how sweet are my lips!
What are you waiting for?
Taste them!
Prabhu, are you awake?
Why aren't you getting up?
Are you waiting for me?
Yes.
Kamali, get up, we need
to perform the ritual today.
We need to prepare.
Yes, we do!
You probably also want me to love you?
You know, I'm ready. Because I like you.
Do you hear me?
Ajamila!
Purnahuti
The Lord joyfully entered your home.
Let him stay here forever,
and bring prosperity and peace with him.
I am your destiny. I am your real life…
Your blessings warm my heart.
Thank you for them…
And you are a lucky man!
You have such a son — Ajamila!
My embrace is gentler than your wife's embrace.
Right, Ajamila?
Yes... Ajamila is my hope!
I want him to become better than me.
What are you waiting for? Taste them!
Ajamila!.. Ajamila!
Good sign, Ajamila!
The Lord sends us a good sign.
By the way!
To you and your son,
with heartfelt gratitude, Lochan Babu.
Money! Money… Coins…!
My love costs something…
…He will have beautiful eyes like yours…
And let the chin be like his grandfather's.
Okay.
He will have beautiful long fingers…
And when he grows up, he will be tall,
even taller than you…
Kamali, do you really think this is possible?
My mother always said,
that parents should first imagine their child,
and only then give birth.
The Lord will definitely give us such a son,
as we create in our minds.
Ajamila, it's actually so simple!
Well… maybe…
Let's sit down here!
Madhava, Gopala… Narayana!
That's what we will call him, Ajamila…
Our son…
Our little one… our treasure.
Narayana. It's so affectionate. My Narayana!
Have you already imagined him?
Of course! I imagine him well.
How do you manage that?
What?
Well… imagining, what his eyes,
what his hands will be like.
what name we'll give him.
I just close my eyes and see all this…
Kamali, dear, let's go home.
Home, why? We are having such a good time walking.
I'm feeling unwell.
Something feels not right…
Is your head hurting?
Prabhu, do you even hear me?
Huh? What? Ah… I hear you, I hear.
Yes, I hear you…
Now everything will be fine.
You will feel better soon.
Just lie down a bit, and you'll feel better.
Oh Lord, what's happening to me?
This has never happened before.
Why can't I get her out of my head?
I don't want this! Where is my mind?
Where is my piety? What am I doing?
It's not too late to stop!
My wife, my Kamali, I can't treat her like this.
You probably also want to be with me
here in the forest, where no one sees us?
Because you like me…
…And if you want to find me, you will….
…My love costs something….
Forgive me… I can't… Her hands… Voice… I can't…
Well, you know, if you have money - come in, but if not…
Not today, but there will be tomorrow… You know that.
When you have some, then you can come…
You can't treat me like this,
I won't leave you today,
I've left everything to come to you…
Let me go! It hurts!
Let me go… And stop acting like a prude!
Let her go!
Who are you?
Well, come in since you've come. I've been waiting!
Now I understand why you didn't want to let me in!
You were waiting for this… Brahman…
And what about you?
Me? Oh, I will leave and never come back again.
And you… Very soon
…Will turn into… .
Well?
You'll become an old woman no one needs!
Be happy, Brahman.
We'll meet again.
Well, hello, Brahman Ajamila.
Hello… uh…
Varsha. That's my name.
Hello, Varsha.
I thought Brahmans sleep at this time.
But look, Brahmans are fully awake and wandering.
So…
You're not in a hurry?
Well then, I am not in a hurry either… Let's go…
Ajamila…
Well, come to me…
Ajamila!
Yes, Gurudev…
Once long ago, I asked you…
Are you ready to follow
the principles of religion to the end of your life
…What did you answer me then?
That I am ready, Gurudev…
Ajamila...
Ajamila, is that all? What else?
You were gone almost a day,
you come and calmly go to sleep?
Did you forget anything?
No, Ajamila.
Now you will explain everything to me.
Where have you been?
Why did you make me and your wife worry?
And where is the money that was donated to us?
It was my money!
I earned it! And now forget it!
There's no more money.
How dare you raise your voice at me?
Leave me alone!
Let's go, daughter…
Let it be…
Where were you?
And where is the money that was donated to us?
It was my money, I earned it,
forget about it, there's no more money!
Leave me alone!
Father!
You left me early in the morning,
and now look — it's noon.
Only a little time has passed…
I wanted to sleep, but I couldn't.
They didn't let me...
Who didn't let you?
Well... father... and... wife.
Whose wife?
Mine.
So you're married?
Yes, but it's nothing serious.
Well, if it's not serious for you,
it's even less so for me.
So, you have a family... Good...
And what did you tell them?
What could I tell them?
Do you not care?
...Probably not.
Though now it's easier.
Just three days ago,
it was very hard for me.
But then something changed.
Something inside me burned out.
I no longer want to think
and weigh every step.
And to be afraid of what others will say.
I've done that my whole life.
I want to breathe freely,
to live without fear and remorse.
After that meeting with you...
there, in the forest...
I couldn't think of anything else but you.
Neither my family nor my duties,
— nothing could make me forget you...
your hands... your voice... your eyes...
I don't want to play the role of
a faithful husband and loving son,
when here inside me is a burning fire.
I can't, and I don't want to...
I just want to be with you...
only with you...
So what... have you fallen in love with me?
Yes...
Have you really found something special in me?
Oh! You don't even know how wonderful you are!
You are my perfection.
You are life itself to me!
I just can't live without you!
I want to be only with you... only with you...
Where is he?
I just saw Ajamila...
He went into the house of a well-known harlot.
I thought so.
Will you follow him?
No. He couldn't be held back by a young wife,
nor by the path of religion he has followed for so long.
If he has made his choice, what can I do?
It's all my fault.
I invested everything I had in Ajamila.
But he made his own choice.
In an instant, the Lord rid me of my pride,
my hopes, my expectations...
My good name...
All I can do now is pray
that the Lord doesn't leave him.
So what are we going to do?
What do you mean?
You've been living with me
for several days now...
Your money has long run out.
And you don't have any new money.
And all my... admirers...
You chased them away...
If you're worried about money,
that's not a problem for me.
Really? That's good news.
Yes. It was never a problem for me.
And where will we live?
Live?..
We can live at my place.
I will bring you to my house.
You'll have a separate room.
If you agree to be with me -
I'll provide for you.
Tell me, do Brahmans chant something every day?
You have some mantras, don't you?
Three times a day…
A hymn to praise the Sun God…
Three times a day.
And when was the last time you chanted them?
Well, probably last week.
And that was the last time.
Because then you found love?
Oh come on, I really do love you.
Love... I believe...
You don't just give up everything like that...
And I don't...
Okay, okay. I understand...
Tell your family that I am... a maid.
If they believe it, of course.
Tell your wife...
Although, say whatever you want...
But remember, I won't work for you.
You will be the one bringing money to me...
For my love... Got it?
We still have time...
how shall we spend it?
Come up to me, I'll whisper it in your ear.
You know how much I adore you...
Ajamila... You have come!
You have returned!
Is this your wife?
Prabhu... Who is this woman?
Kamali, meet Varsha.
Why has she come to our house?
She will help you with the household.
Prabhu, am I not managing by myself?
So what, I am going to live here?
Yes...
And... she... where will she live?
There...
Ajamila, I need a bed here.
I need shelves for clothes,
and boxes for jewelry.
You will buy me jewelry, won't you?
I remember, you promised…
And tell her not to hover over me.
This is now my home too.
And we will live here together.
Wait... Where are you going to?
Now, every time she wants to cry,
you'll run to comfort her?
Do you think that's normal?
She is my wife!
And so? I need attention too.
You don't want me to get upset, do you?
Alright
I want to spend this night in the yard.
I can no longer and do not want
to stay in this house.
Bring out a bed for me.
Ajamila, come to your father.
What is it, father?
My time has come, there is no one else
for me to think about but the Lord.
And I won't stay here anymore.
I will leave... I hope
it will be easier for you.
Let's go, daughter...
Ajamila, it's getting dark.
It's time for us to go to bed.
And you know -
I need all your attention and care.
Alright. Ajamila,
I am waiting for you...
I am waiting for you…
Father... Father... why?
It hurts so much!
It is so painful for me!
The stars are so beautiful tonight!
They have always been like this,
as long as I can remember.
I look at them every day.
My days are not like one another,
but the stars always remain the same.
Oh Supreme Lord, Master of my life,
You are unchanging,
like the stars in the sky.
And unchanging is Your love for us.
Yet we, blinded by our own pain,
cannot see Your love in our lives...
Oh my Narayana, oh Merciful One,
I ask You,
help me to open my heart
enter into it...
I am waiting for You...
Who is there?
My Lord, is it You?
I see You... I recognize You!
How beautiful You are...
You have come for me...
You Yourself have come for me!..
I am ready to go.
Father! Father! Father!
Your father died last night.
Father!
I pray to the Almighty that He gives you
spiritual wisdom and strength
to never stray from the path of
righteousness and virtue.
Do not leave me, I need your strength.
My blessings will never leave you, son,
you can always count on me.
And you will come to see me
in the ashram, won't you?
Of course, son... We will see
each other constantly.
That's good, that's so good!
Father! What have I done?
...what have I done...
Not only your father died tonight...
Tonight, your wife also died.
What?.. What are you saying, Kamali?..
The Kamali who once married Ajamila,
a man of duty and honor
No longer exists.
I can no longer stay here...
I want to leave.
Are you letting me go?
I let you go... Kamali...
Thank you, Prabhu. Please forgive me.
I couldn't be the wife you deserved.
No... you were everything to me...
Kamali... Kamali...
Forgive me if you can.